Leave your expectations at the door
Velvet Goldmine is a drama, music film directed by Todd Haynes.
Almost a decade since larger-than-life glam-rock enigma Brian Slade disappeared from public eye, an
investigative journalist is on assignment to uncover the truth behind his former idol.
Curt Wild, played by Ewan McGregor.
Brian Slade, played by Jonathan Rhys Meyers.
Mandy Slade, played by Toni Collette.
Arthur Stuart, played by Christian Bale.
Jerry Devine, played by Eddie Izzard.
Shannon, played by Emily Woof.
Velvet Goldmine is a 1998 musical drama film written and directed by
Todd Haynes from a story by Haynes and James Lyons.
It is set in Britain during the glam rock days of the early 1970s, and tells the story
of fictional bisexual pop star Brian Slade, who faked his own death.
The film was nominated for the Palme d'Or at the 1998 Cannes Film
Festival and won the award for the Best Artistic Contribution.
Sandy Powell received a BAFTA Award for Best Costume Design and was
nominated for an Academy Award for Best Costume Design.
The film uses non-linear storytelling to achieve exposition while
interweaving the vignettes of its various characters.
The film explores themes of great britain, poetry,
narration, bisexuality, glam rock.
The tone is emotional.